<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN" "journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:lang="en" article-type="rapid-communication" dtd-version="2.3">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">molbank</journal-id>
      <journal-title>Molbank</journal-title>
      <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="publisher">Molbank</abbrev-journal-title>
      <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Molbank</abbrev-journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1422-8599</issn>
      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>MDPI</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/M822</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">molbank-2014-M822</article-id>
      <article-categories>
        <subj-group>
          <subject>Short Note</subject>
        </subj-group>
      </article-categories>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>5-(6-Hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethylchroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic Acid Methyl Ester</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Chen</surname>
            <given-names>Kuan-Hua</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af1-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">1</xref>
          <xref rid="af2-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">2</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Dai</surname>
            <given-names>Chang-Feng</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af3-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">3</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Hwang</surname>
            <given-names>Tsong-Long</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af4-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">4</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Sung</surname>
            <given-names>Ping-Jyun</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af1-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">1</xref>
          <xref rid="af2-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">2</xref>
          <xref rid="af5-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">5</xref>
          <xref rid="af6-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">6</xref>
          <xref rid="af7-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="aff">7</xref>
          <xref rid="c1-molbank-2014-M822" ref-type="corresp">*</xref>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <aff id="af1-molbank-2014-M822"><label>1</label>Graduate Institute of Marine Biotechnology, Department of Life Science and Institute of Biotechnology, National Dong Hwa University, Pingtung 944, Taiwan; E-Mail: <email>asdfgh0213@gmail.com</email></aff>
      <aff id="af2-molbank-2014-M822"><label>2</label>National Museum of Marine Biology and Aquarium, Pingtung 944, Taiwan</aff>
      <aff id="af3-molbank-2014-M822"><label>3</label>Institute of Oceanography, National Taiwan University, Taipei 106, Taiwan; E-Mail: <email>corallab@ntu.edu.tw</email></aff>
      <aff id="af4-molbank-2014-M822"><label>4</label>Graduate Institute of Natural Products, Chang Gung University, Taoyuan 333, Taiwan; E-Mail: <email>htl@mail.cgu.edu.tw</email></aff>
      <aff id="af5-molbank-2014-M822"><label>5</label>Department of Marine Biotechnology and Resources and Asia-Pacific Ocean Research Center, National Sun Yat-sen University, Kaohsiung 804, Taiwan</aff>
      <aff id="af6-molbank-2014-M822"><label>6</label>Graduate Institute of Natural Products, Kaohsiung Medical University, Kaohsiung 807, Taiwan</aff>
      <aff id="af7-molbank-2014-M822"><label>7</label>Chinese Medicine Research and Development Center, China Medical University Hospital, Taichung 404, Taiwan</aff>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="c1-molbank-2014-M822"><label>*</label> Author to whom correspondence should be addressed; E-Mail: <email>pjsung@nmmba.gov.tw</email></corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
        <day>21</day>
        <month>04</month>
        <year>2014</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <month>06</month>
        <year>2014</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>2014</volume>
      <issue>2</issue>
      <elocation-id>M822</elocation-id>
      <history>
        <date date-type="received">
          <day>10</day>
          <month>02</month>
          <year>2014</year>
        </date>
        <date date-type="accepted">
          <day>14</day>
          <month>04</month>
          <year>2014</year>
        </date>
      </history>
      <permissions>
        <copyright-statement>&#xA9; 2014 by the authors; licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</copyright-statement>
        <copyright-year>2014</copyright-year>
        <license>
          <p>This article is an open access article distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons Attribution license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/).</p>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
        <p>A natural diastereomeric mixture of 5-(6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethyl-chroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester (<bold>1</bold>), was isolated from the soft coral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic>. The structure of <bold>1</bold> was elucidated by spectroscopic methods and <bold>1</bold> displayed a significantly inhibitory effect on the generation of superoxide anion by human neutrophils.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group>
        <kwd><italic>Sinularia arborea</italic></kwd>
        <kwd>tocopherol</kwd>
        <kwd>superoxide anion</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <sec sec-type="intro">
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <p>Octocorals belonging to the genus <italic>Sinularia</italic> have been proved to be rich sources of interesting secondary metabolites. The octocoral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic> (phylum Cnidaria, class Anthozoa, subclass Octocorallia, order Alcyonacea, family Alcyoniidae) was studied, as their organic extract was found to show meaning signals in NMR studies. In previous studies on the chemical constituents of the soft coral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1-molbank-2014-M822">1</xref>], six new diterpenoids, arbolides A&#x2013;C, (+)-sarcophytol T, sinularbols A and B, along with a trihydroxysteroid, crassarosterol A, were isolated [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2-molbank-2014-M822">2</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3-molbank-2014-M822">3</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4-molbank-2014-M822">4</xref>]. In the continuing studies on this interesting species, a mixture of diastereoisomers, 5-(6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethylchroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester (<bold>1</bold>), was isolated (<xref ref-type="scheme" rid="molbank-2014-M822-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>). In this paper, we describe the isolation, structure determination and bioactivity of compound <bold>1</bold>.</p>
	  </sec>
	  <sec>
      <title>Results and Discussion</title>
      <p>5-(6-Hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethylchroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester (<bold>1</bold>) was isolated as a colorless oil. Its molecular formula was established as C<sub>20</sub>H<sub>3</sub><sub>0</sub>O<sub>4</sub> from a sodium salt ion at <italic>m/z</italic> 357 in the ESIMS and further supported by the HRESIMS at <italic>m/z</italic> 357.20365 (calcd. for C<sub>20</sub>H<sub>3</sub><sub>0</sub>O<sub>4</sub>Na, 357.20363), thus implying six degrees of unsaturation. The presence of hydroxy and ester groups in <bold>1</bold> were evidenced by IR absorptions at &#x3C5;<sub>max</sub> 3,450 and 1,727 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>. From the <sup>13</sup>C and DEPT spectral data, six tetrasubstituted olefins were deduced from the signals at &#x3B4;<sub>C</sub> 145.40, 144.59, 122.58, 121.04, 118.48 and 117.25. A methyl esterified carboxyl group was supported by the <sup>13</sup>C-NMR signals at &#x3B4;<sub>C</sub> 177.28 (C), 51.45 (CH<sub>3</sub>) and the <sup>1</sup>H-NMR signal (<xref ref-type="table" rid="molbank-2014-M822-t001">Table 1</xref>) at &#x3B4;<sub>H</sub> 3.67 (3H, s, -OMe). Comparison of the <sup>13</sup>C-NMR and DEPT spectra with the molecular formula indicated that there must be an exchangeable proton, requiring the presence of a hydroxy group. From the above data, four degrees of unsaturation were accounted for and <bold>1</bold> must be a compound with two rings.</p>
      <p>From the <sup>1</sup>H&#x2013;<sup>1</sup>H COSY spectrum of <bold>1</bold> (<xref ref-type="table" rid="molbank-2014-M822-t001">Table 1</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molbank-2014-M822-f001">Figure 1</xref>), the separate spin systems of H<sub>2</sub>-3/H<sub>2</sub>-4 and H<sub>2</sub>-1'/H<sub>2</sub>-2'/H<sub>2</sub>-3'/H-4'/H<sub>3</sub>-4a' were differentiated. These data, together with the key HMBC correlations between protons and quaternary carbons (<xref ref-type="table" rid="molbank-2014-M822-t001">Table 1</xref> and <xref ref-type="fig" rid="molbank-2014-M822-f001">Figure 1</xref>), such as H<sub>3</sub>-2a, H<sub>2</sub>-4/C-2; H<sub>2</sub>-4, H<sub>3</sub>-5a/C-4a; H<sub>2</sub>-4, H<sub>3</sub>-5a/C-5; H<sub>3</sub>-5a/C-6; H<sub>3</sub>-7a, H<sub>3</sub>-8a/C-7; H<sub>3</sub>-7a, H<sub>3</sub>-8a/C-8; H<sub>2</sub>-4/C-8b; and H<sub>3</sub>-4a'/C-5', established the main carbon skeleton of <bold>1</bold>. The vinyl methyls at C-5, C-7 and C-8 were confirmed by the HMBC correlations noted, thus, the remaining hydroxy group is positioned at C-6, an oxygen-bearing olefin carbon at &#x3B4;<sub>C</sub> 144.59. Based on the above findings, the structure of <bold>1</bold> is similar in structure to &#x3B1;-tocopherol. A set of additional carbon signals observed in the <sup>13</sup>C-NMR spectrum of <bold>1</bold> (<xref ref-type="table" rid="molbank-2014-M822-t001">Table 1</xref>) supported the presence diastereoisomers. The stereochemistry of chiral carbons C-2 and C-4' was not determined at this stage.</p>
      <p>It was found that the <sup>1</sup>H and <sup>13</sup>C-NMR data of <bold>1</bold> are almost identical to those of a known synthetic compound, 5-(6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethyl-chroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester, that was shown to exist as a set of diastereoisomers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5-molbank-2014-M822">5</xref>]. However, compound <bold>1</bold> has not been isolated previously from any natural sources.</p>
      <p>In a previous study, the cembranoid, arbolide C, which was also isolated from <italic>S. arborea</italic>, showed an inhibitory effect on the release of elastase (IC<sub>50</sub> = 16.99 &#x3BC;M) by human neutrophils [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4-molbank-2014-M822">4</xref>]. The <italic>in vitro</italic> anti-inflammatory effects of <bold>1</bold> was examined; <bold>1</bold> displayed an inhibitory effect on the generation of superoxide anion (IC<sub>50</sub> = 7.42 &#x3BC;M), but not active in inhibition of elastase release by human neutrophils, respectively.</p>
    </sec>
    <sec sec-type="methods">
      <title>Experimental </title>
      <sec>
        <title>General</title>
        <p>Infrared spectra were recorded on a Varian Diglab FTS 1000 FT-IR spectrometer (Varian Inc., Palo Alto, CA, USA); peaks are reported in cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>. NMR spectra were recorded on a Varian Mercury Plus 400 NMR spectrometer (Varian Inc.) using the residual CHCl<sub>3</sub> signal (&#x3B4;<sub>H</sub> 7.26 ppm) as the internal standard for <sup>1</sup>H-NMR and CDCl<sub>3</sub> (&#x3B4;<sub>C</sub> 77.1 ppm) for <sup>13</sup>C-NMR. Coupling constants (<italic>J</italic>) are given in Hz. ESIMS and HRESIMS were recorded using a Bruker 7 Tesla solariX FTMS system (Bruker, Bremen, Germany). Column chromatography was performed on silica gel (230&#x2013;400 mesh, Merck, Darmstadt, Germany). TLC was carried out on precoated Kieselgel 60 F<sub>254</sub> (0.25 mm, Merck); spots were visualized by spraying with 10% H<sub>2</sub>SO<sub>4</sub> solution followed by heating. The normal phase HPLC (NP-HPLC) was performed using a system comprised of a Hitachi L-7110 pump (Hitachi Ltd. Tokyo, Japan), a Hitachi L-2455 photodiode array detector (Hitachi Ltd.) and a Rheodyne 7725 injection port (Rheodyne LLC. Rohnert Park, CA, USA). A normal phase column (Supelco Ascentis<sup>&#xAE;</sup> Si Cat #:581515-U, 25 cm &#xD7; 21.2 mm, 5 &#xB5;m, Sigma-Aldrich, St. Louis, MO, USA) was used for NP-HPLC. The reverse phase HPLC (RP-HPLC) was performed using a system comprised of a Hitachi L-7100 pump (Hitachi Ltd.), a Hitachi L-2455 photodiode array detector (Hitachi Ltd.), a Rheodyne 7725 injection port (Rheodyne LLC.) and a Varian Polaris 5 C-18-A column (25 cm &#xD7; 10 mm, 5 &#x3BC;m).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec>
        <title>Animal Material</title>
        <p>Specimens of the octocoral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic> [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1-molbank-2014-M822">1</xref>] were collected by hand using SCUBA equipment off the coast of southern Taiwan on October, 2012, and stored at &#x2212;20 &#xB0;C until extraction. A voucher specimen (NMMBA-TWSC-1200X) was deposited in the National Museum of Marine Biology and Aquarium, Taiwan.</p>
      </sec>
      <sec>
        <title>Extraction and Isolation</title>
        <p>The freeze-dried and minced material of <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic> (wet weight 1.6 kg, dry weight 576 g) were minced and extracted with ethyl acetate (EtOAc). The extract (12.5 g) was separated by silica gel and eluted using a mixture of <italic>n</italic>-hexane/EtOAc in a stepwise fashion from 100:1 to pure EtOAc to yield 11 fractions A&#x2013;K. Fraction E was purified by NP-HPLC, using a mixture of dichloromethane and methanol (90:1, flow rate: 2.0 mL/min) to yield 26 subfractions E1&#x2013;E26. Fraction E20 was repurified by NP-HPLC, using a mixture of <italic>n</italic>-hexane and acetone (10:1, flow rate: 2.0 mL/min) to yield 9 subfractions E20A&#x2013;E20I. Fraction E20G was separated by RP-HPLC, using a mixture of methanol and water (83:17, flow rate: 1.0 mL/min) to yield 5-(6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethylchroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester (<bold>1</bold>, 6.2 mg, <italic>t</italic><sub>R</sub> = 27 min) as a colorless oil; IR (neat) &#x3BD;<sub>max</sub> 3450, 1727 cm<sup>&#x2212;1</sup>; <sup>1</sup>H (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) and <sup>13</sup>C (100 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) NMR data, see <xref ref-type="table" rid="molbank-2014-M822-t001">Table 1</xref>; ESIMS: <italic>m/z</italic> 357 (M+Na)<sup>+</sup>; HRESIMS: <italic>m/z</italic> 357.20365 (calcd for C<sub>20</sub>H<sub>30</sub>O<sub>4</sub>Na, 357.20363).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec>
        <title>Generation of Superoxide Anions by Human Neutrophils</title>
        <p>Human neutrophils were obtained by means of dextran sedimentation and Ficoll centrifugation. Measurements of superoxide anion generation were carried to previously described procedures [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6-molbank-2014-M822">6</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7-molbank-2014-M822">7</xref>]. Briefly, superoxide anion production was assayed by monitoring the superoxide dismutase-inhibitable reduction of ferricytochrome <italic>c</italic>. LY294002 (2-morpholin-4-yl-8-phenylchromen-4-one), a phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase inhibitor, was used as a positive control (IC<sub>50</sub> = 4.00 &#x3BC;M) for superoxide anion generation.</p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
  <app-group>
    <app id="app1-molbank-2014-M822">
        <title>Supplementary materials</title>
        <supplementary-material id="molbank-2014-M822-s001" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2014-M822-s001-mod.mol">
   <label>Supplementary File 1</label>
</supplementary-material>
        <supplementary-material id="molbank-2014-M822-s002" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2014-M822-s001.mol">
   <label>Supplementary File 2</label>
</supplementary-material>
    </app>
</app-group>
    <ack>
      <title>Acknowledgments</title>
      <p>This research was supported by grants from the National Dong Hwa University; the National Museum of Marine Biology and Aquarium; the Division of Marine Biotechnology, Asia-Pacific Ocean Research Center, National Sun Yat-sen University; and the National Science Council (Grant No. NSC 102-2325-B-291-001 and 101-2320-B-291-001-MY3), Taiwan, awarded to P.-J.S.</p>
    </ack>
    <notes>
      <title>Author Contributions</title>
      <p>Ping-Jyun Sung designed the whole experiment and contributed to manuscript preparation. Kuan-Hua Chen researched data and wrote the mansucript. Chang-Feng Dai and Tsong-Long Hwang analyzed the data and performed data acquisition. All authors read and approved the finnal manuscript.</p>
    </notes>
    <notes>
      <title>Conflict of Interest</title>
      <p>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</p>
    </notes>
    <ref-list>
      <title>References</title>
      <ref id="B1-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>1.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Verseveldt</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Octocorallia from North-Western Madagascar (Part II)</article-title>
          <source>Zool. Verh.</source>
          <year>1971</year>
          <volume>117</volume>
          <fpage>1</fpage>
          <lpage>73</lpage>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B2-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>2.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>K.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dai</surname>
              <given-names>C.-F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lu</surname>
              <given-names>M.-C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>J.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>J.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Su</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>W.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sung</surname>
              <given-names>P.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Secondary Metabolites from the Soft Coral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic></article-title>
          <source>Mar. Drugs</source>
          <year>2013</year>
          <volume>11</volume>
          <fpage>3372</fpage>
          <lpage>3380</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/md11093372</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24005902</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B3-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>3.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>K.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dai</surname>
              <given-names>C.-F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hwang</surname>
              <given-names>T.-L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>C.-Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>J.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>J.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wu</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sheu</surname>
              <given-names>J.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>W.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sung</surname>
              <given-names>P.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Discovery of novel diterpenoids from <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic></article-title>
          <source>Mar. Drugs</source>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>12</volume>
          <fpage>385</fpage>
          <lpage>393</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/md12010385</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24445307</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B4-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>4.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>L.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chen</surname>
              <given-names>K.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Dai</surname>
              <given-names>C.-F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hwang</surname>
              <given-names>T.-L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>W.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wen</surname>
              <given-names>Z.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wu</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sung</surname>
              <given-names>P.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>New cembranoids from the soft coral <italic>Sinularia arborea</italic></article-title>
          <source>Nat. Prod. Commun.</source>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>9</volume>
          <fpage>361</fpage>
          <lpage>362</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24689215</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B5-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>5.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Pope</surname>
              <given-names>S.A.S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Burtin</surname>
              <given-names>G.E.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Clayton</surname>
              <given-names>P.T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Madge</surname>
              <given-names>D.J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Muller</surname>
              <given-names>D.P.R.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>New synthesis of (&#xB1;)-&#x3B1;-CMBH and its confirmation as a metabolite of &#x3B1;-tocopherol (vitamin E)</article-title>
          <source>Bioorg. Med. Chem.</source>
          <year>2001</year>
          <volume>9</volume>
          <fpage>1337</fpage>
          <lpage>1343</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/S0968-0896(01)00010-4</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B6-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>6.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>S.-C.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>P.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ho</surname>
              <given-names>C.-M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kuo</surname>
              <given-names>C.-Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hung</surname>
              <given-names>M.-F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Huang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>W.-Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chan</surname>
              <given-names>K.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hwang</surname>
              <given-names>T.-L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Propofol inhibits superoxide production, elastase release, and chemotaxis in formyl peptide-activated human neutrophils by blocking formyl peptide receptor 1</article-title>
          <source>J. Immunol.</source>
          <year>2013</year>
          <volume>190</volume>
          <fpage>6511</fpage>
          <lpage>6519</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.4049/jimmunol.1202215</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23670191</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B7-molbank-2014-M822">
        <label>7.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Yu</surname>
              <given-names>H.-P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hsieh</surname>
              <given-names>P.-W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chung</surname>
              <given-names>P.-J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kuo</surname>
              <given-names>L.-M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hwang</surname>
              <given-names>T.-L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>2-(2-Fluorobenzamido)benzoate ethyl ester (EFB-1) inhibits superoxide production by human neutrophils and attenuates hemorrhagic shock-induced organ dysfunction in rats</article-title>
          <source>Free Radic. Biol. Med.</source>
          <year>2011</year>
          <volume>50</volume>
          <fpage>1737</fpage>
          <lpage>1748</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.freeradbiomed.2011.03.026</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21457779</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
    <sec sec-type="display-objects">
      <title>Figure, Scheme and Table</title>
      <fig id="molbank-2014-M822-sch001" position="float">
        <object-id pub-id-type="pii">molbank-2014-M822-sch001_Scheme 1</object-id>
        <label>Scheme 1</label>
        <caption>
          <p>The structure of 5-(6-hydroxy-2,5,7,8-tetramethyl-chroman-2-yl)-2-methyl-pentanoic acid methyl ester (<bold>1</bold>).</p>
        </caption>
        <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2014-M822-sch001.tif"/>
      </fig>
      <fig id="molbank-2014-M822-f001" position="float">
        <label>Figure 1</label>
        <caption>
          <p><sup>1</sup>H&#x2013;<sup>1</sup>H COSY and selective key HMBC correlations (protons&#x2192;quaternary carbons) for <bold>1</bold>.</p>
        </caption>
        <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2014-M822-g001.tif"/>
      </fig>
      <table-wrap id="molbank-2014-M822-t001" position="float">
        <object-id pub-id-type="pii">molbank-2014-M822-t001_Table 1</object-id>
        <label>Table 1</label>
        <caption>
          <p><sup>1</sup>H (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) and <sup>13</sup>C (100 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) NMR data, <sup>1</sup>H&#x2013;<sup>1</sup>H COSY and HMBC correlations for <bold>1</bold>.</p>
        </caption>
        <table>
          <thead>
            <tr>
              <th align="center" valign="middle" style="border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin">Position</th>
              <th align="center" valign="middle" style="border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin">&#x3B4;<sub>H</sub> (<italic>J</italic> in Hz)</th>
              <th colspan="3" align="center" valign="middle" style="border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin">&#x3B4;<sub>C</sub>, Multiple</th>
              <th align="center" valign="middle" style="border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin"><sup>1</sup>H&#x2013;<sup>1</sup>H COSY</th>
              <th align="center" valign="middle" style="border-top:solid thin;border-bottom:solid thin">HMBC (H&#x2192;C)</th>
            </tr>
          </thead>
          <tbody>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">74.25</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2a</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.22 s</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">23.67</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">23.65</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-2, -3, -1', </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">3</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.78 m</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">31.55</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>2</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-4</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-4</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">4</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2.60 t (6.8)</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">20.69</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>2</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-3</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-2, -3, -4a, -5, -8b</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">4a</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">118.48</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">5</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">117.25</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">5a</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2.11 s</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">11.26</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-4a, -5, -6</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">6</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">144.59</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">7</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">121.04</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">7a</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2.10 s</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">11.75</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-7, -8</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">8</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">122.58</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">8a</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2.16 s</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">12.19</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-7, -8</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">8b</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">145.40</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.59 m, 1.51 m</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">39.35</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">39.31</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>2</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-2'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">n.o. <italic><sup>a</sup></italic></td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.44 m</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">21.30</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">21.26</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>2</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-1', H<sub>2</sub>-3'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">n.o.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">3'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.66 m, 1.42 m</td>
              <td colspan="2" align="center" valign="middle">34.20</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>2</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-2', H-4'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">n.o.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">4'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">2.46 sext (5.6)</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">39.40</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">39.36</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H<sub>2</sub>-3', H<sub>3</sub>-4a'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">n.o.</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">4a'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">1.15 d (6.8) </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">17.06</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">17.02</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">H-4'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-3', -4', -5'</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">5'</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">177.28</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">177.24</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">5'-OCH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">3.67 s</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">51.45</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">51.44</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">CH<sub>3</sub></td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle">C-5'</td>
            </tr>
            <tr>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin">6-OH</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin">4.20 br s</td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin"> </td>
              <td align="center" valign="middle" style="border-bottom:solid thin"> </td>
            </tr>
          </tbody>
        </table>
        <table-wrap-foot>
          <fn>
            <p><sup>a</sup> n.o. = not observed.</p>
          </fn>
        </table-wrap-foot>
      </table-wrap>
    </sec>
  </back>
</article>
