<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//NLM//DTD Journal Publishing DTD v2.3 20070202//EN" "journalpublishing.dtd">
<article xmlns:mml="http://www.w3.org/1998/Math/MathML" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xml:lang="en" article-type="rapid-communication" dtd-version="2.3">
  <front>
    <journal-meta>
      <journal-id journal-id-type="publisher-id">molbank</journal-id>
      <journal-title>Molbank</journal-title>
      <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="publisher">Molbank</abbrev-journal-title>
      <abbrev-journal-title abbrev-type="pubmed">Molbank</abbrev-journal-title>
      <issn pub-type="epub">1422-8599</issn>
      <publisher>
        <publisher-name>MDPI</publisher-name>
      </publisher>
    </journal-meta>
    <article-meta>
      <article-id pub-id-type="doi">10.3390/M873</article-id>
      <article-id pub-id-type="publisher-id">molbank-2015-M873</article-id>
      <article-categories>
        <subj-group>
          <subject>Short Note</subject>
        </subj-group>
      </article-categories>
      <title-group>
        <article-title>1-[2,3-Bis(tetradecyloxy)propyl]-3-[2-(piperazin-1-yl)ethyl]urea</article-title>
      </title-group>
      <contrib-group>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Grijalvo</surname>
            <given-names>Santiago</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af1-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">1</xref>
          <xref rid="af2-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">2</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>N&#xFA;&#xF1;ez</surname>
            <given-names>Samuel</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af1-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">1</xref>
          <xref rid="af2-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">2</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="author">
          <name>
            <surname>Eritja</surname>
            <given-names>Ramon</given-names>
          </name>
          <xref rid="af1-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">1</xref>
          <xref rid="af2-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="aff">2</xref>
          <xref rid="c1-molbank-2015-M873" ref-type="corresp">*</xref>
        </contrib>
        <contrib contrib-type="editor">
          <name>
            <surname>Haider</surname>
            <given-names>Norbert</given-names>
          </name>
          <role>Academic Editor</role>
        </contrib>
      </contrib-group>
      <aff id="af1-molbank-2015-M873"><label>1</label>Biomedical Research Networking Center in Bioengineering, Biomaterials and Nanomedicine (CIBER-BBN), Barcelona E-08034, Spain; E-Mails: <email>santiago.grijalvo@iqac.csic.es</email> (S.G.); <email>snunezpe9@gmail.com</email> (S.N.)</aff>
      <aff id="af2-molbank-2015-M873"><label>2</label>Department of Chemical and Biomolecular Nanotechnology, Institute of Advanced Chemistry of Catalonia (IQAC-CSIC), Jordi Girona 18-26, Barcelona, Catalonia E-08034, Spain</aff>
      <author-notes>
        <corresp id="c1-molbank-2015-M873"><label>*</label> Author to whom correspondence should be addressed; E-Mail: <email>recgma@cid.csic.es</email>; Tel.: +34-93-400-6145; Fax: +34-93-204-5904.</corresp>
      </author-notes>
      <pub-date pub-type="epub">
        <day>11</day>
        <month>11</month>
        <year>2015</year>
      </pub-date>
      <pub-date pub-type="collection">
        <month>12</month>
        <year>2015</year>
      </pub-date>
      <volume>2015</volume>
      <issue>4</issue>
      <elocation-id>M873</elocation-id>
      <history>
        <date date-type="received">
          <day>29</day>
          <month>09</month>
          <year>2015</year>
        </date>
        <date date-type="accepted">
          <day>09</day>
          <month>11</month>
          <year>2015</year>
        </date>
      </history>
      <permissions>
        <copyright-statement>&#xA9; 2015 by the authors; licensee MDPI, Basel, Switzerland.</copyright-statement>
        <copyright-year>2015</copyright-year>
        <license>
          <p>This article is an open access article distributed under the terms and conditions of the Creative Commons Attribution license (http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/).</p>
        </license>
      </permissions>
      <abstract>
        <p>Starting from 2,3-bis(tetradecyloxy)propan-1-amine (<bold>1</bold>), the synthesis of the target compound 1-[2,3-bis(tetradecyloxy)propyl]-3-[2-(piperazin-1-yl)ethyl]urea (<bold>2</bold>) is reported. The title compound was characterized by <sup>1</sup>H-NMR, <sup>13</sup>C-NMR and ESI/MS analysis.</p>
      </abstract>
      <kwd-group>
        <kwd>amino lipid</kwd>
        <kwd>cationic lipid</kwd>
        <kwd>delivery</kwd>
      </kwd-group>
    </article-meta>
  </front>
  <body>
    <sec id="sec1-molbank-2015-M873" sec-type="intro">
      <title>1. Introduction</title>
      <p>Non-viral vectors have emerged in the last decade as a promising approach for the treatment of diseases involving DNA and RNA molecules. [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B1-molbank-2015-M873">1</xref>] There is a good number of examples in which non-viral vectors have been linked with nucleic acids by using covalent approaches or combined with each other by optimized formulations. These two approaches have allowed the synthesis of the anticipated nucleic acid conjugates or complexes, respectively. Cationic lipids [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B2-molbank-2015-M873">2</xref>], dendrimers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B3-molbank-2015-M873">3</xref>], cell-penetrating peptides [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B4-molbank-2015-M873">4</xref>] or polymers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B5-molbank-2015-M873">5</xref>] have become the most common units used to improve the nucleic acids efficacy in cellular transfection processes. Despite the existence of an arsenal of non-viral vectors, the use of cationic lipids remains one of the most used transfecting agents due to their simple preparation, biodegradability and their wide use in clinical trials.</p>
      <p>The pioneering work carried out by Felgner <italic>et al</italic>. in 1987 [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B6-molbank-2015-M873">6</xref>] demonstrated how a synthetic glycerol-based cationic lipid (DOTMA) was able to interact with DNA and impart cellular uptake, leading to the expected lipid-DNA complex fusion with the plasma membrane. Since then, a wide number of cationic lipids has been reported and tested as potential non-viral carriers [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B7-molbank-2015-M873">7</xref>].</p>
      <p>As a general structure, synthetic glycerol-based cationic lipids are mostly made of a glycerol backbone which contains two points of diversity: a hydrocarbonated alkyl chain and a cationic head group (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="molbank-2015-M873-f001">Figure 1</xref>). This has led to the synthesis of novel cationic lipids series in a combinatorial fashion in order to optimize the initial &#x201C;lead compound.&#x201D; Examples of these combinatorial libraries have been reported [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B8-molbank-2015-M873">8</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B9-molbank-2015-M873">9</xref>].</p>
      <p>Recently, we reported the ability of a synthetic amino lipid (<bold>1</bold>) to interact with plasmid DNA and impart efficiently cellular uptake. These studies were carried out both <italic>in vitro</italic> and <italic>in vivo</italic>, obtaining promising transfection results (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="molbank-2015-M873-f001">Figure 1</xref>A) [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10-molbank-2015-M873">10</xref>,<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B11-molbank-2015-M873">11</xref>]. This transfecting agent contained a double-tailed hydrocarbonated alkyl chain with ether linkages, a glycerol backbone and a primary amino group as a cationic head. As part of our ongoing efforts in the synthesis of novel cationic lipids to improve the cellular uptake of genetic materials, we herein report the synthesis of 1-[2,3-bis(tetradecyloxy)propyl]-3-[2-(piperazin-1-yl)ethyl]urea (<bold>2</bold>), a glycerol-based cationic lipid which contains two hydrocarbonated alkyl ether chains of fourteen atoms of carbon and a piperazine moiety that would act as a cationic head. The covalent linkage between the hydrophobic and the hydrophilic part was accomplished by forming the anticipated urea derivative (<xref ref-type="fig" rid="molbank-2015-M873-f001">Figure 1</xref>B).</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec2-molbank-2015-M873" sec-type="results">
      <title>2. Results and Discussion </title>
      <p>The synthesis of the title cationic lipid (<bold>2</bold>) is displayed in <xref ref-type="scheme" rid="molbank-2015-M873-sch001">Scheme 1</xref>. As previously reported, <italic>N</italic>-Boc-protected diol (<bold>3</bold>) was used as a starting material for the synthesis of 2,3-bis(tetradecyloxy)propan-1-amine (<bold>1</bold>). Compound (<bold>3</bold>) was subjected to alkylation by phase-transfer catalyst under basic conditions at 60 &#xB0;C followed by a Boc-deprotection reaction under acidic conditions to achieve the anticipated amino lipid compound (<bold>1</bold>) in quantitative yield [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B10-molbank-2015-M873">10</xref>].</p>
      <p>The introduction of the piperazine derivative (<bold>4</bold>) and the synthesis of the title compound (<bold>2</bold>) was carried out following two consecutive reactions: Firstly, the conversion of the corresponding primary amine (<bold>1</bold>) to the intermediate 4-nitrophenyl chloroformate at room temperature; and secondly, the displacement of the 4-nitrophenyl moiety promoted by the protected <italic>N</italic>-Boc-piperazine amino derivative (<bold>4</bold>). These reactions afforded the anticipated protected urea compound after purifying by flash chromatography (CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub>:MeOH 6%) in good yield (81%). Finally, the <italic>N</italic>-Boc protecting group was conveniently removed by treatment with 10% trifluoroacetic acid (TFA) in an organic solvent like dichloromethane (CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub>) at room temperature with high yields (85%). Following treatment with TFA, the amine salt was properly liberated with polymer-supported carbonate base (Amberlite IRA 900 NaCO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x2212;</sup> form) in ethyl acetate at room temperature [<xref ref-type="bibr" rid="B12-molbank-2015-M873">12</xref>]. This protocol generated the expected compound (<bold>2</bold>) in good yield (85%).</p>
    </sec>
    <sec id="sec3-molbank-2015-M873">
      <title>3. Experimental Section</title>
      <sec id="sec3dot1-molbank-2015-M873">
        <title>3.1. General Methods</title>
        <p>All reagents, dry solvents and chemicals were purchased from Sigma-Aldrich (Tres Cantos, Madrid, Spain) and were used as received without further purification. All reactions were carried out in oven-dried glassware under inert atmosphere of argon. Analytical thin layer chromatography (TLC) was done on E. Merck silica gel 60 F254 plates (Merck, Darmstadt, Germany), visualized by UV and stained with phosphomolybdic acid. Flash chromatography was carried out on silica gel SDS 0.063&#x2013;0.2 mm/70&#x2013;230 mesh (Solvent Documentation Syntheses, Peypin, France). <sup>1</sup>H- and <sup>13</sup>C-NMR spectra were recorded at 25 &#xB0;C on a Varian Mercury 400 MHz spectrometer (Varian Inc., Palo Alto, CA, USA). Tetramethylsilane (TMS) was used as an internal reference (0 ppm) for <sup>1</sup>H spectra recorded in CDCl<sub>3</sub> and the residual signal of the solvent (77.16 ppm) for <sup>13</sup>C spectra. Chemical shifts were reported in part per million (ppm) in the &#x3B4; scale, coupling constants (<italic>J</italic>) in Hz and multiplicity as follows: bs (broad singlet), m (multiplet), t (triplet). Electrospray ionization mass spectra (ESI-MS) were recorded on a Micromass ZQ instrument (Waters Corporation, Milford, MA, USA) with single quadrupole detector coupled to an HPLC, and high-resolution (HR) ESI-MS on an Agilent 1100 LC/MS-TOF instrument (Agilent Technologies, Santa Clara, CA, USA).</p>
      </sec>
      <sec id="sec3dot2-molbank-2015-M873">
        <title>3.2. 1-[2,3-Bis(tetradecyloxy)propyl]-3-[2-(piperazin-1-yl)ethyl]urea <italic>(<bold>2</bold>)</italic></title>
        <p>(a) 2,3-bis(tetradecyloxy)propan-1-amine (<bold>1</bold>) (25 mg; 0.052 mmol) was dissolved in a mixture of anhydrous CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub> and THF (1:1) (total volume: 1.0 mL). Then, DIEA (1.5 eq) and <italic>p</italic>-nitrophenyl chloroformate (15.7 mg; 0.078 mmol) were carefully added at room temperature. The mixture was stirred at room temperature for 5 h. The solvent was reduced in vacuo obtaining a yellow oil. The crude was used without further purification in the next reaction step.</p>
        <p>(b) The resulting product (30 mg; 0.046 mmol) was dissolved in anhydrous DMF (1.0 mL) and the <italic>N</italic>-Boc-protected piperazine amine derivative (<bold>4</bold>) was added dropwise together with TEA (1.0 eq). The resulting mixture was stirred overnight at room temperature. The solvent was removed under reduced pressure and purified by flash chromatography (CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub>:MeOH 6%). A yellowish oil was obtained (81%).</p>
        <p>(c) Finally, the resulting compound (27.5 mg; 0.037 mmol) was dissolved in a mixture of 10% TFA in CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub> (1.0 mL). The reaction was stirred at room temperature for 1 h. The solvent was reduced in vacuo and the anticipated trifluoroacetate salt was used without further purification. The dried crude was dissolved in AcOEt (2.0 mL) and polymer-supported carbonate base (Amberlite IRA 900 NaCO<sub>3</sub><sup>&#x2212;</sup> form) (10.0 eq) was added. The mixture was stirred for 1 h at room temperature (until pH of the organic layer was basic). Finally, the resin was filtered off and the filtrate was removed under vacuum obtaining the expected cationic lipid derivative (<bold>2</bold>) (20.1 mg; 0.031 mmol) with good yields (85%). </p>
        <p><sup>1</sup>H-NMR (400 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) &#x3B4; (ppm) 5.54 (bs, N<underline>H-CO</underline>), 5.26 (bs, N<underline>H</underline>-CO), 3.52 (m, 1H), 3.44 (m, 8H), 3.26 (m, 2H; -N-CH<sub>2</sub>-C<underline>H</underline><sub>2</sub>-NH-), 3.18 (m, 4H; piperazine ring), 2.78 (m, 4H; piperazine ring), 2.60 (m, 2H; -N-C<underline>H</underline><sub>2</sub>-CH<sub>2</sub>-NH-), 1.51 (m, 4H; 2 C<underline>H</underline><sub>2</sub> alkyl chain), 1.23 (m, 44H; alkyl chain), 0.85 (t, <italic>J</italic> = 6.6 Hz; 6H; 2 C<underline>H</underline><sub>3</sub>-CH<sub>2</sub>).</p>
        <p><sup>13</sup>C-NMR (125 MHz, CDCl<sub>3</sub>) &#x3B4; (ppm) 161.8 (<underline>C</underline>O), 161.4, 77.6 (<underline>C</underline>H-O), 71.8 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-O), 70.4 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-O), 58.1 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-O), 48.6 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-N), 40.8 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-N), 40.7 (HO-CH-<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-N), 34.8 (CH<sub>2</sub>-<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-Pip), 31.9 (CH<sub>2</sub>-<underline>C</underline>H<sub>2</sub>-N), 29.9, 29.7, 29.6, 29.5, 29.4, 29.4, 29.3, 28.1, 26.0, 25.9, 22.6 (alkyl chain), 14.0 (<underline>C</underline>H<sub>3</sub>-C).</p>
        <p>HRMS (ESI<sup>+</sup>) <italic>m</italic>/<italic>z</italic> calcd for C<sub>38</sub>H<sub>79</sub>N<sub>4</sub>O<sub>3</sub> [M + H]<sup>+</sup> 639.6147 found 639.6147.</p>
        <p><sup>1</sup>H-NMR, <sup>13</sup>C-NMR and ESI-MS spectra for the title compound <bold>2</bold> are available in the <xref ref-type="app" rid="app1-molbank-2015-M873">Supplementary Information</xref>.</p>
      </sec>
    </sec>
  </body>
  <back>
  <app-group>
    <app id="app1-molbank-2015-M873">
      <title>Supplementary materials</title>
       <supplementary-material id="molbank-2015-M873-s001" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2015-M873-s001.pdf">
        <label>Supplementary File 1</label>
       </supplementary-material>
	   <supplementary-material id="molbank-2015-M873-s002" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2015-M873-s002-mod.mol">
        <label>Supplementary File 2</label>
       </supplementary-material>
	   <supplementary-material id="molbank-2015-M873-s003" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2015-M873-s002.mol">
        <label>Supplementary File 3</label>
       </supplementary-material>
    </app>
  </app-group>
    <ack>
      <title>Acknowledgments</title>
      <p>This work is supported by grants of the Spanish Ministry of Economy (MINECO) (CTQ2014-52588-R, RTC-2014-2038-1, CTQ2014-61758-EXP), Generalitat de Catalunya (2014/SGR/624) and the Instituto de Salud Carlos III (CB06_01_0019). CIBER-BBN is an initiative funded by the VI National R&amp;D&amp;i Plan 2008-2011, Iniciativa Ingenio 2010, Consolider Program, CIBER Actions and financed by the Instituto de Salud Carlos III with assistance from the European Regional Development Fund.</p>
    </ack>
    <notes>
      <title>Author Contributions</title>
      <p>This work is part of a project that has been going on in the RE research group in the field of DNA and RNA delivery. The experimental work was carried out by SG and SN The manuscript was written and corrected by all authors.</p>
    </notes>
    <notes>
      <title>Conflicts of Interest</title>
      <p>The authors declare no conflict of interest.</p>
    </notes>
    <ref-list>
      <title>References</title>
      <ref id="B1-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>1.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Won</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Lim</surname>
              <given-names>K.S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>Y.-H.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Intracellular organelle-targeted non-viral gene delivery systems</article-title>
          <source>J. Control. Release</source>
          <year>2011</year>
          <volume>152</volume>
          <fpage>99</fpage>
          <lpage>109</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2011.01.013</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">21255626</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B2-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>2.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Duan</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>S.-B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>B.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Yang</surname>
              <given-names>B.-L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhi</surname>
              <given-names>D.-F.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The biological routes of gene delivery mediated by lipid-based non-viral vectors</article-title>
          <source>Exp. Opin. Drug Deliv.</source>
          <year>2009</year>
          <volume>6</volume>
          <fpage>1351</fpage>
          <lpage>1361</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/17425240903287153</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19780710</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B3-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>3.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Marvaniya</surname>
              <given-names>H.M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Parikh</surname>
              <given-names>P.K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Patel</surname>
              <given-names>V.R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Modi</surname>
              <given-names>K.N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Sen</surname>
              <given-names>D.J.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Dendrimer nanocarriers as versatile vectors in gene delivery</article-title>
          <source>J. Chem. Pharm. Res.</source>
          <year>2010</year>
          <volume>2</volume>
          <fpage>97</fpage>
          <lpage>108</lpage>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B4-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>4.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Lehto</surname>
              <given-names>T.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kurrikoff</surname>
              <given-names>K.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Langel</surname>
              <given-names>U.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Cell-penetrating peptides for the delivery of nucleic acids</article-title>
          <source>Exp. Opin. Drug Deliv.</source>
          <year>2012</year>
          <volume>9</volume>
          <fpage>823</fpage>
          <lpage>836</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1517/17425247.2012.689285</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">22594635</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B5-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>5.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>W.J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Kim</surname>
              <given-names>S.W.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Efficient siRNA delivery with non-viral polymeric vehicles</article-title>
          <source>Pharm. Res.</source>
          <year>2009</year>
          <volume>26</volume>
          <fpage>657</fpage>
          <lpage>666</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1007/s11095-008-9774-1</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">19015957</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B6-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>6.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Felgner</surname>
              <given-names>P.L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Gadek</surname>
              <given-names>T.R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Holm</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Roman</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Chan</surname>
              <given-names>H.W.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wenz</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Northrop</surname>
              <given-names>J.P.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ringold</surname>
              <given-names>G.M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Danielsen</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Lipofection: A highly efficient, lipid-mediated DNA-transfection procedure</article-title>
          <source>Proc. Natl. Acad. Sci. USA</source>
          <year>1987</year>
          <volume>84</volume>
          <fpage>7413</fpage>
          <lpage>7417</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1073/pnas.84.21.7413</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">2823261</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B7-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>7.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Zhi</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhang</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Cui</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhao</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zhao</surname>
              <given-names>D.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>The headgroup evolution of cationic lipids for gene delivery</article-title>
          <source>Bioconjug. Chem.</source>
          <year>2013</year>
          <volume>24</volume>
          <fpage>487</fpage>
          <lpage>519</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/bc300381s</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23461774</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B8-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>8.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Li</surname>
              <given-names>L.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wang</surname>
              <given-names>F.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Wu</surname>
              <given-names>Y.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Davidson</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Levkin</surname>
              <given-names>P.A.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Combinatorial synthesis and high-throughput screening of alkyl amines for nonviral gene delivery</article-title>
          <source>Bioconjug. Chem.</source>
          <year>2013</year>
          <volume>24</volume>
          <fpage>1543</fpage>
          <lpage>1551</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1021/bc400158w</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">23909648</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B9-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>9.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Akinc</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Zumbuehl</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Goldberg</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Leshchiner</surname>
              <given-names>E.S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Busini</surname>
              <given-names>V.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Hossain</surname>
              <given-names>N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Bacallado</surname>
              <given-names>S.A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Nguyen</surname>
              <given-names>D.N.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Fuller</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Alvarez</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <etal/>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>A combinatorial library of lipid-like materials for delivery of RNAi therapeutics</article-title>
          <source>Nat. Biotechnol.</source>
          <year>2008</year>
          <volume>26</volume>
          <fpage>561</fpage>
          <lpage>569</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1038/nbt1402</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">18438401</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B10-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>10.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Puras</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Z&#xE1;rate</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Agirre</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>D&#xED;az-Tahoces</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Avil&#xE9;s-Trigueros</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grijalvo</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eritja</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Fen&#xE1;ndez</surname>
              <given-names>E.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Pedraz</surname>
              <given-names>J.L.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>A novel formulation based on 2,3-di(tetradecyloxy)propan-1-amine cationic lipid combined with polysorbate 80 for efficient gene delivery to the retina</article-title>
          <source>Pharm. Res.</source>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>31</volume>
          <fpage>1665</fpage>
          <lpage>1675</lpage>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B11-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>11.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Puras</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mashal</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Z&#xE1;rate</surname>
              <given-names>J.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Agirre</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ojeda</surname>
              <given-names>E.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Grijalvo</surname>
              <given-names>S.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Eritja</surname>
              <given-names>R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>D&#xED;az-Tahoces</surname>
              <given-names>A.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Mart&#xED;nez Navarrete</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Avil&#xE9;s-Trigueros</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <etal/>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>A novel cationic noisome formulation for gene delivery to the retina</article-title>
          <source>J. Control. Release</source>
          <year>2014</year>
          <volume>174</volume>
          <fpage>27</fpage>
          <lpage>36</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1016/j.jconrel.2013.11.004</pub-id>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="pmid">24231407</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
      <ref id="B12-molbank-2015-M873">
        <label>12.</label>
        <citation citation-type="journal">
          <person-group person-group-type="author">
            <name>
              <surname>Baxendale</surname>
              <given-names>I.R.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Brusotti</surname>
              <given-names>G.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Matsuoka</surname>
              <given-names>M.</given-names>
            </name>
            <name>
              <surname>Ley</surname>
              <given-names>S.V.</given-names>
            </name>
          </person-group>
          <article-title>Synthesis of nornicotine, nicotine and other functionalized derivatives using solid-supported reagents and scavengers</article-title>
          <source>J. Chem. Soc., Perkin Trans. 1</source>
          <year>2002</year>
          <fpage>143</fpage>
          <lpage>154</lpage>
          <pub-id pub-id-type="doi">10.1002/chin.200221164</pub-id>
        </citation>
      </ref>
    </ref-list>
    <sec sec-type="display-objects">
      <title>Figure and Scheme</title>
      <fig id="molbank-2015-M873-f001" position="float">
        <label>Figure 1</label>
        <caption>
          <p>Di(<italic>O</italic>-alkyl)glycerol-based cationic lipids general structure. (<bold>A</bold>) Compound (<bold>1</bold>) was successfully evaluated as a transfecting agent; (<bold>B</bold>) The title compound (<bold>2</bold>) was designed as a second-generation molecule from our &#x201C;lead compound <bold>1</bold>&#x201D;.</p>
        </caption>
        <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2015-M873-g001.tif"/>
      </fig>
      <fig id="molbank-2015-M873-sch001" position="float">
        <object-id pub-id-type="pii">molbank-2015-M873-sch001_Scheme 1</object-id>
        <label>Scheme 1</label>
        <caption>
          <p>Synthesis of the title compound <bold>2</bold>.</p>
        </caption>
        <graphic xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink" xlink:href="molbank-2015-M873-sch001.tif"/>
		<p><italic>Reagents and conditions</italic>: a. 4-nitrophenyl chloroformate (1.5 eq), CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub>:THF (1:1), DIEA (1.5 eq), r.t., 5 h; b. <bold>4</bold> (1.0 eq), TEA (1.0 eq), DMF, r.t., overnight; c. 10% TFA:CH<sub>2</sub>Cl<sub>2</sub>, r.t., 1 h; d. Polymer-supported carbonate (10.0 eq), AcOEt, r.t., 1 h.</p>
      </fig>
    </sec>
  </back>
</article>
